<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<blog-entry>
    <title>Double-strawberry Open-faced Pie</title>
    <subtitle>Adapted From the Pie and Pastry Bible by Rose Levy Beranbaum</subtitle>
    <abstract>My strawberry pie version adapted from the Pie and Pastry Bible by Rose Levy Beranbaum</abstract>
    <author>
        <name>Brian</name>
        <surname>Geiger</surname>
    </author>
    <publication-date>2009-05-28</publication-date>
    <cover-image>"milk-data-and-cookies/images/reuben-mcfeeters-unsplash.jpg"</cover-image>
    <cover-image-caption>Photo by Reuben Mcfeeters on Unsplash</cover-image-caption>
    <content>
        <h1>Ingredients</h1>
        <h4>The Crust</h4>
        <ul>
            <li>200g Cold unsalted Butter, cut into 1/4" cubes</li>
            <li>320g All-Purpose Flour</li>
            <li>3/4 tsp Salt</li>
            <li>126g Heavy Cream</li>
            <li>1 Egg White, lightly beaten</li>
        </ul>
        <h4>The Base Layer</h4>
        <ul>
            <li>85g Lindt White Chocolate (all but one column of a 3.5oz bar)</li>
            <li>4oz Cream Cheese</li>
            <li>2 Tbl sour cream</li>
        </ul>
        <h4>The Cooked Layer</h4>
        <ul>
            <li>1 cup fresh strawberries (after rinsing, drying, hulling, and halving</li>
            <li>2 Tbl Cornstarch</li>
            <li>118g Water</li>
            <li>67g Sugar</li>
            <li>1 Tsp Fresh Lemon Juice</li>
            <li>1 pinch Salt</li>
        </ul>
        <h4>The Fresh Layer</h4>
        <ul>
            <li>Enough whole strawberries, to cover a 9" circle when stood point up, hulled, dried, and rinsed.</li>
            <li>72g Currant Jelly (1/4 cup)</li>
            <li>1 Tbl St. Germain Elderflower Liqueur</li>
        </ul>
        <h1>Directions</h1>
        <h4>The Crust</h4>
        <p>Put 1/3 of the butter into the freezer in a medium-sized mixing bowl.</p>
        <p>Whisk the flour and salt together. Mix in 2/3 of the butter with a pastry cutter until it looks like course meal. Once the butter is mixed with the flour, minimize exposure of the dough to your warm, warm hands, or you will melt the butter.</p>
        <p>Place the butter/salt/flour mixture into a gallon-sized zip-top bag. Add in the last 1/3 of the butter and put the bowl back into the freezer. Get rid of all the air you can and seal the bag. Take your trustiest rolling pin and roll the contents of the bag until the butter turns into flatten flakes. Place the bag into the freezer for 10 minutes or thereabouts. The goal is to reverse any melting from the butter and make it reasonably solid again.</p>
        <p>Take out the bag and the bowl, and transfer all of the dough to the bowl. You will need to scrape the sides of the bag, as the butter will have stuck to it during the rolling. Sprinkle the heavy cream into the mixture and mix. I use a silicone spatula to mix, as it won't melt the butter and it'll resist some of the sticking.</p>
        <p>Put the mixture back into the bag and seal, removing most of the air as before. Knead the dough inside the bag with your fingertips until it sticks together. When you pull it, it should stretch a bit.</p>
        <p>Divide the dough into two 6" discs and refrigerate for anywhere from 1 to 24 hours. 8 hours is ideal. Although you'll only need one of these discs for this pie, as it was a competition, I baked two in case something went horribly, horribly wrong.</p>
        <div class="portlet-msg-alert">Preheat the oven to 450° and let sit at that temperature for another 20-30 minutes.</div>
        <p>Roll out the pie dough into a 13" circle and place into the pie pan. Shape the top as you like. Freeze for at least 20 minutes.</p>
        <p>Dock the sides and bottom of the dough. Crumple a piece of parchment paper, unroll it, and place over the pie, fitting it down close to the dough. Put in your dried beans, rice, or pie weights. Bake for 20 minutes. Carefully remove the weighted parchment paper, cover the top edge of the crust with aluminum foil, and bake for another 5-10 minutes, until the inside of the crust has a light golden tinge and feels more like crust than dough. Let cool for 3 minutes, then brush on the egg white to the sides and bottom. Let cool completely.</p>
        <h4>The Bottom Layer</h4>
        <p>Put the white chocolate into a microwave safe dish and microwave on high for 20 seconds at a time. At the end of each, stir. Repeat until there's more melted bits than solid bits, then keep stirring until all of the solid bits turn into melted bits. Let cool to room temperature.</p>
        <p>In a small mixing bowl, mix the cream cheese with an electric mixer until it's somewhat fluffy and whipped. Add in the cooled white chocolate and mix. Add in the sour cream and mix until combined. Cover the bottom of the pie with this mixture.</p>
        <h4>The Cooked Layer</h4>
        <p>Lightly crush the strawberries with a fork in a small saucepan. Add the sugar, water, salt, lemon juice, and cornstarch. Bring to a boil. Simmer for 1 minute. Pour into a bowl and let cool to room temperature. Stir occasionally during the cooling process. Once cooled, pour over the bottom later of the pie.</p>
        <h4>The Fresh Layer</h4>
        <p>Your strawberries should have the tops cut off so that they could stand up on the a flat surface. Place these point side up on top of the pie.</p>
        <p>In the small saucepan which has been washed and dried, melt the currant jelly until it is melted. It will bubble. Strain into a glass, which will involve a lot of pressing with a spatula. Stir in the St. Germain. Brush this mixture onto the fresh strawberries.</p>
        <h4>The Pie</h4>
        <p>Cool in a refrigerator for an hour or two or overnight. Slice and eat, or slice and serve to judges. If the latter, try to save yourself a slice.</p>
    </content>
    <tags>
        <tag>butter<tag>
        <tag>cornstarch</tag>
        <tag>cream cheese</tag>
        <tag>currant jelly</tag> 
        <tag>lemon</tag> 
        <tag>pie</tag> 
        <tag>strawberry</tag>  
        <tag>sugar</tag>
    </tags>
    <categories>
        <category>recipes</category>
    </categories>
</blog-entry>